Preliminary Guide to the Robert H. Woody papers, 1927-1985
Duke University. University Archives
Robert H. Woody papers 1927-1985.
Woody, Robert H. (Robert Hilliard), 1903-
6 linear feet Extent: 6,000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
Contains the personal and professional papers of Robert Hilliard Woody, a professor of history at Duke University from 1929 to 1970. Types of materials include correspondence, manuscripts, short writings, vitae, certificates, diplomas, committee reports, printed material, photographs, 8 mm films, and VHS tapes. Major subjects include Robert H. Woody, the Civil War, the South, South Carolina, North Carolina, reconstruction, republicans, southern newspapers, biographies, mountain culture, folklore, history instruction, Duke University, the Duke University history department, and the George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana. Major correspondents appearing in the collection include: William Preston Few, Francis B. Simkins, William K. Boyd, William T. Laprade, Francis Warrenton Dawson, Stanly Godbold, Jr., Arthur Hollis Edens, Paul M. Gross, Stanley Godbold, the Southern Historical Association, and the Historical Society of North Carolina. Some materials are restricted. Materials range in date from 1927 to 1985. English.
UA.29.02.0023
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
Gift; 1964; 64-66
Gift; 1966; 66-120
Gift; 1967; 67-91
Gift; 1969;69-176
Transfer; 1973; 74-15
Gift; 1973; 74-35
Gift; 1983; 83-36
Biographical Note
Robert Hilliard Woody was born in 1903 in the Little Cataloochee Creek community of Haywood County in western North Carolina. Woody attended grammar schools in Kentucky and graduated from high school in London, Kentucky in 1923. That fall, he entered Emory University and studied history under Professor Francis Butler Simkins. Woody received his B.Ph. degree from Emory in 1927, then earned an M.A. (1928) and a Ph.D. (1930) from Duke University. Woody's dissertation was part of a collaborative work with mentor Francis Butler Simkins. Their book, South Carolina During Reconstruction (1932), earned the John H. Dunning Prize of the American Historical Association in 1931.
In 1929, Woody began teaching history as a full professor at Duke University. For the first seven years of his teaching career, he taught modern European history. In 1932, he began to teach United States history. Some of his courses were about American colonial history, the United States from 1850-1900, historiography of the South, and the Old South. Woody directed thirty-two doctoral dissertations and at least fifty-eight master's theses. In 1937, Woody reduced his teaching load to part-time so that he could act as the director of the George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana in the Duke University Library. Woody retired from the Department of History in 1970.
Woody took an active approach to documenting history on a personal and professional level. He recorded activities of his vacations, his thoughts on teaching, the Duke University academic climate (including the Gross-Edens Affair), and historical society meetings. Woody corresponded with Duke University colleagues and mentors in the history field: Arthur Hollis Edens, Paul M. Gross, William Preston Few, Francis B. Simkins, William K. Boyd, and William T. Laprade.
Woody published over 220 articles on the Civil War period, southern newspapers, the South, reconstruction, and North Carolina communities. Some article titles are: "The Labor and Immigration Problem of South Carolina During Reconstruction," "Christopher Gadsden and the Stamp Act," "The Army of Northern Virginia," and "Franklin J. Moses, Jr., Scalawag Governor of South Carolina." The culture of Western North Carolina mountain residents were described in his article "Catalochee Reunion." He also wrote significant biographies about William Preston Few, Francis Warrington Dawson, and Civil War statesmen.
Woody was a member of the American Historical Association, the Southern Historical Association, the Mississippi Valley Historical Association, the North Carolina Literary and Historical Association, the South Carolina Historical Association, the Historical Society of North Carolina, and Phi Beta Kappa. Some of his books include: South Carolina During Reconstruction (1932), Republican Newspapers of South Carolina (1936), and The Papers and Addresses of William Preston Few (1951). He was also a contributor to the Dictionary of American Biography and Dictionary of American History. In 1942, he was selected to review Jule B. Warren's History of North Carolina, a textbook for use in public schools that was found to be riddled with errors.
Woody married Louise Wills in 1929. Their children are Dorothy Jean and Stephen Boyd. In 1983, Woody moved from Durham, N.C. to San Diego, California. He died in San Diego in 1985.
Collection Overview
Contains the personal and professional papers of Robert Hilliard Woody, a teacher and historian at Duke University from 1929 to 1970. Materials include correspondence with individuals and professional organizations, films, clippings, and writings (including original Civil War correspondence) pertaining to Woody's research, and manuscript materials for biographies of Civil War statesmen and Duke University President William Preston Few. Major correspondents include colleagues at Duke University: Arthur Hollis Edens, Paul M. Gross, William Preston Few, Francis B. Simkins, William K. Boyd, and William T. Laprade. Correspondence is ordered alphabetically. Films are 8mm format. Some materials are restricted
Subject Headings
American newspapers -- South Carolina -- History; Dawson, Francis Warrington, 1840-1889; Duke University. Dept. of History; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Edens, Arthur Hollis, 1901-; Few, William Preston, 1867-1940; Folklore -- North Carolina; George Washington Flowers Collection of Southern Americana; Godbold, E. Stanly; Gross, Paul Magnus, 1895-1986; Historical Society of North Carolina; History -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Laprade, William Thomas, 1883-1975; North Carolina -- Politics and government; North Carolina -- Social conditions; Reconstruction -- North Carolina; Reconstruction -- South Carolina -- Civil War; Reconstruction -- Southern States; Republican Party (S.C.); Simkins, Francis Butler, 1897-1966; South Carolina -- History -- 1865-; South Carolina -- Economic conditions; South Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1775-1783; South Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; South Carolina -- Social conditions; Southern Historical Association; Statesmen -- United States -- Biography; United States -- history -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Biography; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Reconstruction; Woody, Robert H. (Robert Hilliard), 1903-; Film
Contents of Collection
- Container List:
  - Recollections, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dinner honoring Professor Woody, November 9, 1973. Festschrift announced. (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Abbott, W.W. (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Adams, Randolph G. (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Akerman, Hugh (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Alden, John (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - American Historical Review (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Archives Committee, Raleigh, N.C. (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Askew, W.C. (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - Awards (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - Baker, Maury (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - Baldwin, (Dean) Alice (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - Barnwell, R.W., Sr. (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - Barnwell, R.W., Jr. (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - Barry, R.S. (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - Basler, Roy P. (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - Beale, Howard K. (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - Beers, Burton F. (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - Bell, Albert Atwood, Jr. (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - Bennett, Floyd S. (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - Bennett, William L. (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - Block, Robert Hoyt (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - Bornet, Vaughan (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - Bowles, Robert C. (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Branscomb, H. (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - Braverman, Howard (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - Brice, Ashbel (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - Briceland, Alan (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - Brousard, James H. (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - Bryan, J.C. (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - Buchanan, Carol Phipps (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Burrows, Edward F. (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - Candler, Frances G. (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - Cannon, Carl F., Jr. (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - Cappon, Lester J. (Folder 37, Box 1)
  - Carolina Charter Corporation (Folder 38, Box 1)
  - Carroll, Eber Malcolm (Folder 39, Box 1)
  - Chaffin, Nora C. (Folder 40, Box 1)
  - Chambers, M.B.C. (Folder 41, Box 1)
  - Civil War History,(James I. Robertson, Editor) (Folder 42, Box 1)
  - Clark, Thomas D. (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - Cockrell, Monroe F. (Folder 44, Box 1)
  - Coleman, J. Winston (Folder 45, Box 1)
  - Colvin, Thomas Bethel (Folder 46, Box 1)
  - Committees (Folder 47, Box 1)
  - Commonwealth--Studies Center (Folder 48, Box 1)
  - Committee on Publications (Folder 49, Box 1)
  - Daughters of the Confederacy (Folder 50, Box 1)
  - Confederate Centennial Commission, 1959-1961 (Folder 51, Box 1)
  - Copper, Mildred Jo (Folder 52, Box 1)
  - Cotterill, R.S. (Folder 53, Box 1)
  - Corbitt, David Leroy (Folder 54, Box 1)
  - Coulter, E.M. (Folder 55, Box 1)
  - Crisp, James (Folder 56, Box 1)
  - Crittenden, C.C.--Sir Walter Award, 1954 (Folder 57, Box 1)
  - Crittenden, C.C.--Writings for North Carolina Historical Review (Folder 58, Box 1)
  - Crittenden, C.C. (Folder 59, Box 1)
  - Cunningham, H.H. (Folder 60, Box 1)
  - Cunningham, Noble E., Jr. (Folder 61, Box 1)
  - Curry, R.W. (Folder 62, Box 1)
  - Curtiss, John S. (Folder 63, Box 1)
  - Daniel, Harrison Cunningham (Folder 64, Box 1)
  - Davis, Lambert (Folder 65, Box 1)
  - Dawson, Francis Warrington (Folder 66, Box 1)
  - Dean, Gordon (Folder 67, Box 1)
  - DesChamps, Margaret (Folder 68, Box 1)
  - Dean of Graduate School, Marcus E. Hobbs (Folder 69, Box 1)
  - Delaney, Norman (Folder 70, Box 1)
  - Director of Graduate Studies (Folder 71, Box 1)
  - Dorris, J.T. (Folder 72, Box 1)
  - Drozdowski, Gene (Folder 73, Box 1)
  - Duke University Council (Folder 74, Box 1)
  - Duke University Council on Research (Folder 75, Box 1)
  - Duke University Library, ca. 1953 (Folder 76, Box 1)
  - Duke University Press (Folder 77, Box 1)
  - Duke University Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1954-1961 (Folder 78, Box 1)
  - Duncan, Bingham (Folder 79, Box 1)
  - Durden, Robert F. (Folder 80, Box 1)
  - Easterby, J.H. (Folder 81, Box 1)
  - Edens, Arthur Hollis (Folder 82, Box 1)
  - Emory University newsletter (Folder 83, Box 1)
  - England, J. Merton (Folder 84, Box 1)
  - Erwin, Clyde A. (Folder 85, Box 1)
  - Faculty Council (Folder 86, Box 1)
  - Farish, Hunter D. (Folder 87, Box 1)
  - Fellowship in history (Folder 88, Box 1)
  - Few, Benjamin F. (Folder 89, Box 1)
  - Few, Ellie (Folder 90, Box 1)
  - Few, William Preston, biography and correspondence (Folder 91, Box 1)
  - Few, William Preston, biography notes (Folder 92, Box 1)
  - Few, William Preston, biography, draft 1 (Folder 93, Box 1)
  - Few, William Preston, biography, draft 2 (Folder 94, Box 1)
  - Few, William Preston, biography, draft 3 (Folder 95, Box 1)
  - Fields, J.E., Dr. (Folder 96, Box 1)
  - Flanders, Ralph B. (Folder 97, Box 1)
  - Flowers, R.L. (Folder 98, Box 1)
  - Flowers, W.W. (Folder 99, Box 1)
  - Flowers collection, 1952 (Folder 100, Box 1)
  - Flowers collection, 1958 (Folder 101, Box 1)
  - Flowers collection (Folder 102, Box 1)
  - Flowers collection committee (Folder 103, Box 1)
  - Folmsbee, Stanley J. (Folder 104, Box 1)
  - Forest History Foundation (Folder 105, Box 1)
  - Fries, Adelaide L. (Folder 106, Box 1)
  - Ganyard, Robert Loyal (Folder 107, Box 1)
  - Garber, Paul N. (Folder 108, Box 1)
  - Garrison, Curtis W. (Folder 109, Box 1)
  - Geary, James J. (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Graduate Office, 1941-1949 (Folder 111, Box 2)
  - Graduate office, 1950- (Folder 112, Box 2)
  - Goff, Richard (Folder 113, Box 2)
    The contents of the folder "Goff, Richard" are RESTRICTED.
  - Gray, Joe D. (Folder 114, Box 2)
  - Green, E.L. (Folder 115, Box 2)
  - Green, Fletcher (Folder 116, Box 2)
  - Gregorie, A.K. (Folder 117, Box 2)
  - Grimball, Berkeley (Folder 118, Box 2)
  - Gross, Paul M. (Folder 119, Box 2)
  - Hall, Arthur (Folder 120, Box 2)
  - Hallowell, John H. (Folder 121, Box 2)
  - Hamilton, Tom (Folder 122, Box 2)
  - Hamilton, W.B. (Folder 123, Box 2)
  - Harwell, R.B. (Folder 124, Box 2)
  - Hayes Memorial (Folder 125, Box 2)
  - Hay, T.R. (Folder 126, Box 2)
  - Heartman, Martha E. (Folder 127, Box 2)
  - Henry, R.S. (Folder 128, Box 2)
  - Hilty, Hiram (Folder 129, Box 2)
  - Historical Society of North Carolina (Folder 130, Box 2)
  - Historical Society of North Carolina, committee (Folder 131, Box 2)
  - Historical Society of North Carolina, program (Folder 132, Box 2)
  - History Department, regulations and minutes (Folder 133, Box 2)
  - Hobbs, Marcus (Folder 134, Box 2)
  - Holley, I.B. (Folder 135, Box 2)
  - Holton, Holland (Folder 136, Box 2)
  - Honeycutt, Ava L., Jr. (Folder 137, Box 2)
  - Hoole, W.S. (Folder 138, Box 2)
  - Huff, A.V., Jr. (Folder 139, Box 2)
  - Indiana Magazine of History (Folder 140, Box 2)
  - Ingram, Bern (Folder 141, Box 2)
  - Inman, Anne (Folder 142, Box 2)
  - James A. Rogers Library, Francis Marion College, Florence, S.C. (Folder 143, Box 2)
  - Johnson, Ludwell H. (Folder 144, Box 2)
  - Jones, Houston Gwynne (Folder 145, Box 2)
  - Jordan, Weymouth T. (Folder 146, Box 2)
  - Jordan, William H. (Folder 147, Box 2)
  - Journal of Southern History (Folder 148, Box 2)
  - Journal of Southern History, Detweiler (Folder 148, Box 2)
  - Journal of Southern History, J.M. England (Folder 150, Box 2)
  - King, Doris (Folder 151, Box 2)
  - King, Willard L. (Folder 152, Box 2)
  - Kirwan, A.D. (Folder 153, Box 2)
  - Lanning, John Tate (Folder 154, Box 2)
  - Lefler, Hugh T. (Folder 155, Box 2)
  - Lemple, Leland L. (Folder 156, Box 2)
  - Lerner, Eugene M. (Folder 157, Box 2)
  - Logan, S. Frank (Folder 158, Box 2)
  - Luthin, Reinhard H. (Folder 159, Box 2)
  - Luvaas, Jay (Folder 160, Box 2)
  - McAnear, Beverly (Folder 161, Box 2)
  - McCaim, James R. (Folder 162, Box 2)
  - McCain, Paul M. (Folder 163, Box 2)
  - McCloy, S.T. (Folder 164, Box 2)
  - McLaurin, Jean (Folder 165, Box 2)
  - McLendau, Jonathan C. (Folder 166, Box 2)
  - McMillan, James B. (Folder 167, Box 2)
  - McMurtrie, Douglas C. (Folder 168, Box 2)
  - McMurtry, R. Gerald (Folder 169, Box 2)
  - Marby, W.A. (Folder 170, Box 2)
  - Maryland Historical Society (Folder 171, Box 2)
  - Manarin, Louis (Folder 172, Box 2)
  - Mann, Harold D. (Folder 173, Box 2)
  - Matchette, Robert Berry (Folder 174, Box 2)
  - Matthews, Don G. (Folder 175, Box 2)
  - Matthews, A.J. (Folder 176, Box 2)
  - Matthews, Roy, Jr. (Folder 177, Box 2)
  - Mayflower award (Folder 178, Box 2)
  - Methodist College, Fayetteville (Folder 179, Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous writings (Folder 180, Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous writings (Folder 181, Box 2)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association (Folder 182, Box 2)
  - Mitchell, Norma Taylor (Folder 183, Box 2)
  - Moore, A.B. (Folder 184, Box 2)
  - Morse, Thomas W. (Folder 185, Box 2)
  - Murray, Paul (Folder 186, Box 2)
  - Nelson, E.W. (Folder 187, Box 2)
  - Nettels, Curtis P. (Folder 188, Box 2)
  - Nevins, Allan (Folder 189, Box 2)
  - Nichols, Roy (Folder 190, Box 2)
  - Noggle, Burl (Folder 191, Box 2)
  - North Carolina Historical Review (Folder 192, Box 2)
  - North Carolina Literary and Historical Association (Folder 193, Box 2)
  - University of North Carolina Press (Folder 194, Box 2)
  - O'Donnell, James (Folder 195, Box 2)
    The contents of the folder "O'Donnell, James" are RESTRICTED.
  - Oliver, George B. (Folder 196, Box 2)
    The contents of the folder "Oliver, George B." are RESTRICTED.
  - Parker, Harold T. (Folder 197, Box 2)
  - Patton, James W. (Folder 198, Box 2)
  - Pearce, H.J. (Folder 199, Box 2)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Folder 200, Box 2)
  - Pegg, C.H., summer session (Folder 201, Box 2)
    The contents of the folder "Pegg, C.H., summer session" are RESTRICTED.
  - James K. Polk commission (Folder 202, Box 2)
  - Posey, W.B. (Folder 203, Box 2)
  - Potter, David M. (Folder 204, Box 2)
  - Powell, Ben (Folder 205, Box 2)
  - Prior, Granville T. (Folder 206, Box 2)
  - Publications committee (Folder 207, Box 2)
  - Reid, Robert H. (Folder 208, Box 2)
  - Research Council, Duke University (Folder 209, Box 2)
  - Rice, Carew (Folder 210, Box 2)
  - Richards, Jane (Folder 211, Box 2)
  - Rivers, Robert Hayne (Folder 212, Box 2)
  - Robertson, William Glenn (Folder 213, Box 2)
  - Robert, Joseph Clark (Folder 214, Box 2)
  - Robinson, William M., Jr. (Folder 215, Box 2)
  - Ropp, Ted (Folder 216, Box 2)
  - Russell, Mattie (Folder 217, Box 2)
  - Scheffel, Kenneth (Folder 218, Box 2)
  - Schuyler, Robert Livingston (Folder 219, Box 2)
  - Seale, William, Jr. (Folder 220, Box 2)
  - Simkins, Francis B. (Folder 221, Box 2)
  - Sisk, Glenn N. (Folder 222, Box 2)
  - Smith, Clarence M. (Folder 223, Box 2)
  - Smith, Culver H. (Folder 224, Box 2)
  - Smith, H. Shelton (Folder 225, Box 2)
  - Snider, David Kelley (Folder 226, Box 2)
  - Southern Historical Association (Folder 227, Box 2)
  - Southern Historical Association, council (Folder 228, Box 2)
  - Southern Historical Association, program (Folder 229, Box 2)
  - Southern Historical Association, nominating committee (Folder 230, Box 2)
  - Southern Historical Association, Ramsdell award, 1955-1965, 1958-1959 (Folder 231, Box 2)
  - Sowle, Patrick (Folder 232, Box 2)
  - Stark, John D. (Folder 233, Box 2)
  - Stephens, George M. (Box 3, Folder 234)
  - Stephenson, Wendell H. (Folder 235, Box 3)
  - Stevens, Harry R. (Folder 236, Box 3)
  - Stone, Marjorie S. (Folder 237, Box 3)
  - Stroupe, Henry S. (Folder 238, Box 3)
  - Students, miscellaneous (Folder 239, Box 3)
  - Summer session (Folder 240, Box 3)
  - Summers, Festus P. (Folder 241, Box 3)
  - Sutor, Jack (Folder 242, Box 3)
  - Tally, David K. (Folder 243, Box 3)
  - Talmadge, John E. (Folder 244, Box 3)
  - Tarlton, William S. (Folder 245, Box 3)
  - Taylor, Rosser H. (Folder 246, Box 3)
  - Taylor, Rosser H. (Folder 247, Box 3)
  - TePaske, John J. (Folder 248, Box 3)
  - Thomas, Robert N. (Folder 249, Box 3)
  - Todd, Richard C. (Folder 250, Box 3)
  - Todd, Richard C. and Confederate Finance (Folder 251, Box 3)
  - Trent, Mark P., Jr. (Folder 252, Box 3)
  - Trinity College Historical Society (Folder 253, Box 3)
  - U.S. Quarterly Book List (Folder 254, Box 3)
  - Van Dusen, Albert E. (Folder 255, Box 3)
  - Van Hook, J.O. (Folder 256, Box 3)
  - Veith, Paul F. (Folder 257, Box 3)
  - Wade, John D., Georgia Review (Folder 258, Box 3)
  - Wallace, Lillian Parker (Folder 259, Box 3)
  - Wannamaker, W.H. (Folder 260, Box 3)
  - Wallace, Wesley H. (Folder 261, Box 3)
  - Watson, Richard (Folder 262, Box 3)
  - Weaver, Herbert (Folder 263, Box 3)
  - Webb, John M. (Folder 264, Box 3)
  - Weissfield, Jerry C. (Folder 265, Box 3)
  - Whitener, D.J. (Folder 266, Box 3)
  - Wilburn, H.C. (Folder 267, Box 3)
  - Wilkerson, M.M. (Folder 268, Box 3)
  - Williams, Gary (Folder 269, Box 3)
  - Williams, T. Harry (Folder 270, Box 3)
  - William and Mary Quarterly (Folder 271, Box 3)
  - Ziring, Stanley (Folder 272, Box 3)
  - Zuher, R.L. (Folder 273, Box 3)
  - Racine thesis, correspondence, and unfoldered materials (Folder 274, Box 3)
  - Clippings (Folder 275, Box 3)
  - Correspondence and other unfoldered materials (Folder 276, Box 3)
  - South Carolina During Reconstruction (Folder 277, Box 3)
  - General biographical materials, Robert H. Woody (Folder 278, Box 3)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Folder 279, Box 3)
  - Asheville paper, November, 1963 (Folder 280, Box 3)
  - Civil War clippings (Folder 281, Box 3)
  - Civil War, soldier's letters (transcriptions) (Folder 282, Box 3)
  - Civil War memorabilia, printed items (Folder 283, Box 3)
  - Carpetbaggers ("Northerners in the South") (Folder 284, Box 3)
  - Hoor, E., transcripts of "Abolitionists in the South" (Folder 285, Box 3)
  - The Bookmark (Folder 286, Box 3)
  - Berrien, J.W.M. to Baber, ca. 1840 (Folder 287, Box 3)
  - History and the Changing South (Folder 288, Box 3)
  - Jones, C.E., submarine torpedoes in the Civil War, clippings (Folder 289, Box 3)
  - Civil War Centennial Commission, 1958-1969 (Folder 290, Box 3)
  - M. Bryant, University of Tennessee Press (Folder 291, Box 3)
  - Godbold, Stanley, Jr. (Folder 292, Box 3)
  - Godbold, Stanley, Jr. (Folder 293, Box 3)
  - Godbold, Stanley, Jr. (Folder 294, Box 3)
  - Parker-Daniel letters, 1980-1981 (Folder 295, Box 3)
  - American Historical Association (Folder 296, Box 3)
  - Bryan, T. Conn (Folder 297, Box 3)
  - Department of Archives and History (Folder 298, Box 3)
  - Williams, Gary Lee (Folder 299, Box 3)
  - Broussard, James H. (Box 4, Folder 300)
  - Buchanan, Carol Phipps (Folder 301, Box 4)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Folder 302, Box 4)
  - Carolina Charter Corporation, Educational Advisory Board (Folder 303, Box 4)
  - Colton, Joel (Folder 304, Box 4)
  - Daniel, Harrison (Folder 305, Box 4)
  - Davis, Curtis Carroll (Folder 306, Box 4)
  - Delaney, Norman C. (Folder 307, Box 4)
  - Durden, Robert F. (Folder 308, Box 4)
  - Eaton, James N. (Folder 309, Box 4)
  - Edens, A. Hollis (Folder 310, Box 4)
  - Emory University (Folder 311, Box 4)
  - Encyclopedia of Southern History (Folder 312, Box 4)
  - Finnie, Gordon E. (Folder 313, Box 4)
  - Gadsden biography (Folder 314, Box 4)
  - Gadsden, Jeanne (Folder 315, Box 4)
  - Gadsden, Mary J. (Folder 316, Box 4)
  - Gadsden, Philip H. (Folder 317, Box 4)
  - Gadsden, Philip H. correpsondence (Folder 318, Box 4)
  - Graduate students (Folder 319, Box 4)
  - Greene, Jack (Folder 320, Box 4)
  - Huff, A.V. (Folder 321, Box 4)
  - King, Robert T., University of South Carolina Press (Folder 322, Box 4)
  - Francis Marion College, library collection (Folder 323, Box 4)
  - Laprade, William T. (Folder 324, Box 4)
  - Louisiana State University Press (Folder 325, Box 4)
  - McCloy, Shelby T. (Folder 326, Box 4)
  - McCarter, Linda (Folder 327, Box 4)
  - McLean, Ross H. (Folder 328, Box 4)
  - Manarin, Louis (Folder 329, Box 4)
  - Matthews, Antoinette Johnson (Folder 330, Box 4)
  - Matthews, John Michael (Folder 331, Box 4)
  - Mitchell, Norma (Folder 332, Box 4)
  - Moore, Marie D. (Folder 333, Box 4)
  - Dictionary of North Carolina Biography, sketches and drafts (Folder 334, Box 4)
  - Nolan, Louis C. (Buck) (Folder 335, Box 4)
  - North Carolina Department of Archives and History (Folder 336, Box 4)
  - Powell, Bill (Folder 337, Box 4)
  - Rachal, W.M.E. (Folder 338, Box 4)
  - Renberg, James (Folder 339, Box 4)
  - Sandburg, Carl (Folder 340, Box 4)
  - Sanders, Charles R., Jr. (Folder 341, Box 4)
  - Seale, William (Folder 342, Box 4)
  - Snider, David K. (Folder 343, Box 4)
  - South Carolina Historical Association (Folder 344, Box 4)
  - Spalt, Allen E. (Folder 345, Box 4)
  - Stayer, Samuel Nessly (Folder 346, Box 4)
  - Sydnor, Charles S., Jr. and Victor Sydnor (Folder 347, Box 4)
  - Sydnor, Betty (Folder 348, Box 4)
  - Davis, Jefferson, correspondence (Folder 349, Box 4)
    Inclides typewritten copies of the Fourteenth Amendment and printed material (mostly editorial)
  - Hammond, James Henry (Folder 350, Box 4)